SEAN RYAN FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Creative and driven developer with extensive professional experience in digital marketing and communications. My goal is to be a standout member of a forward-thinking development team by combining my talent for writing clean and intuitive code with stellar communication skills.

PROJECTS

Think Tank Source Code | App Hosted on Netlify

A real-time chat application build with React and Firebase

- Implemented a Firebase Realtime Database to store and relate user, room, and message data objects
- Connected database to an interface allowing users to perform create, read and delete operations via the Firebase API

TV Show Database Source Code | App Hosted on Heroku

A UI allowing users to search and learn about thousands of TV shows

- Built a streamlined UI that sends search requests to an Express server
- Wrote endpoints on an Express/Node server to handle client requests
- Connected the server to the <u>TMDb API</u> to retrieve search results
- Tested UI features and API endpoints with Jasmine

Pickipedia Source Code | App Hosted on Heroku

A Wikipedia-style app for chronicling live American roots music in NYC

- Built a full-stack MVC-style application allowing users to create a profile and perform CRUD operation on wikis
- Implemented different access rights and privileges for "basic" and "premium" user roles
- Wrote unit and integration tests with Jasmine

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Freelance Web Developer, Nov. 2019 - Present

Various Clients

 Develop custom landing pages for Léieren Learning Systems using HTML, CSS and JavaScript on the Cornerstone On Demand CMS

Digital Communications Coordinator, Sept. 2015 - Present

Association for Computing Machinery, New York, NY

- Hand code and troubleshoot responsive, cross-client HTML emails for member communications
- Write social media, web, and email marketing content tailored to an audience of software engineers and computing researchers
- Doubled average monthly social follower growth, tripled monthly Google AdWords member acquisitions

Project Manager, Feb. 2012 - Sept. 2015

SIS International Research. New York, NY

- Managed multi-city qualitative and quantitative research projects through initial planning to client delivery
- Moderated focus groups and in-depth interviews for research projects in cities across the US
- Wrote final reports presenting research findings and recommendations to clients

GitHub | Portfolio | LinkedIn | Blog seanpryan89@gmail.com (203) 731-4234

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript

CSS

HTML

Bootstrap

SASS

Git

GitHub

React

NPM

SQL

Postgres

Node.js

Unit Testing

EDUCATION

Bloc

Nov. 2018 - July 2019 Completed Web Developer Track Program

NYU Continuing Education (Front-end Foundations)

Feb. 2018 - Apr. 2018 Front-end end web development with an emphasis on mobile first layout techniques

Hamilton College

Aug. 2007 - May 2011

Degree: B.A. in History, English

Literature